DURAMENTE, THE NEXT TRIPLE CROWN HORSE GIRL
(大鸣大放 下个三冠赛马娘)
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
Remember,
听好了
maintain your pacing during the race.
要在比赛中掌握自己的节奏
Don't be intimidated by your rivals.
不要因为周围的人而自乱阵脚
Yes, sir.
是
NICE NATURE
(优秀素质)
"IKUNO DICTUS, TWIN TURBO" You idiot!
(生野狄杜斯 双涡轮 待兼唐怀瑟) 笨蛋…
DURAMENTE
(大鸣大放)
So far away.
好远
I can't even catch her shadow.
那个背影 远到我追不上
I…
我肯定是…
All good, Kitasan?
还好吗 北部
Well, I was thinking if I put you back on your training too soon after Derby.
没有啦 我在想不是在德比开赛前 练习的间隔太紧了
Maybe that's what's keeping you from concentrating.
可能就是因为这样 让你无法集中精神吧
No, I…
不 我…
You should focus on recuperating for now,
现在就先以消除疲劳为优先吧
so let's call it a day here.
今天就先这样吧
Okay.
我知道了
TOKAI TEIO CAN TEIO SURPASS THE EMPEROR?
(东海帝皇) (帝王能超越皇帝吗)
TEIO'S RACE
(帝皇的比赛)
Today's special is about
今天的特集
Duramente, who won Satsuki Sho and the Japanese Derby.
是夺下了皋月赏和日本德比
DURAMENTE SPECIAL, FUTURE TRIPLE CROWN
(大鸣大放特集 三冠候补) 众所期待她拿下经典三冠的赛马娘
her triple crown this year.
大鸣大放
Thanks to her extraordinary agility, strength,
拥有令人难以想象的速度和力量
and special gait that draws attention,
以及吸引众人目光的独特跑法
"SECOND TO NONE PERFORMANCE"
(力压群雄的表现)
she is often compared to Symboli Rudolf,
可以说是和鲁道夫象征和东海帝皇
"OWNER OF TWO CROWNS SO FAR" and Narita Brian.
(展现惊人实力 达成经典二冠) 以及成田白仁
Duramente reminds everyone
这些历代的明星赛马娘们
"OWNER OF TWO CROWNS SO FAR" of these legendary horse girls.
(展现惊人实力 达成经典二冠) 拥有同等实力
And that is part of her charm.
这就是她所带给所有人的魅力
I aspire, yearn
我一直很憧憬
to be like her.
一直想成为那个人
I thought I could make it.
我以为我做得到
I thought I could shine on the stage
在舞台上闪闪发亮
and be cheered on.
吸引众人目光
I would become a star like my father.
成为像爸爸那样的明星
I wanted to be like that.
心想有朝一日我也要成为那样的人
And one day, that dream took a form.
然后在某一天 那个梦想化为现实
-Tokai Teio made a beeline to the line. -That day…
-东海帝皇向直线冲去了 -就在那天…
There she goes!
她冲出去了
Three racers are vying for the second place.
有三个人在争夺第二名
Tokai Teio!
东海帝皇 是东海帝皇
As if trying to prove herself,
像是在展现彼此资质的不同一般
she pulls further and further ahead.
以一个马身…两个马身的距离 不断地拉大差距
How formidable!
太强了
Tokai Teio
东海帝皇
finished the race in the first place! She did not disappoint!
回应了她那超高人气 以首位之姿冲过终点
What a performance!
太可怕了
And she just debuted. She's so good!
好强哦 新马出道赛居然就有这种表现
Wow.
好厉害
-Wow! -I was drawn to her right away.
-好厉害… -一眼就被她所吸引了
She's fast,
既厉害
beautiful, and awesome.
又漂亮又帅气
If I can
同样身为赛马娘
run like her…
要是能像她那样奔跑的话…
I want to be like Teio.
我想要成为帝皇那样的人
I want to be close to her,
我想要接近她的实力
"FINISHING LINE" to her awesome performance.
(终点) 接近那股帅气 那怕一步都好
I want to run with her
想要和她齐头并进
and admire the same view as her.
跟她看着相同的景色
We will experience the same thing.
去感受那个光景
I want to be a horse girl like that.
我想要成为那样的赛马娘
Regardless of seasons,
无论春夏秋冬
weather,
晴天还是雨天
when I'm going through ups and downs,
开心的时候 失落的时候
when I'm alone or in great company,
一个人的时候 有同伴陪伴的时候
whenever it is,
无论何时
Teio's shining silhouette
在我心里让我支持下去的
is what
就是帝皇的背影
keeps me going.
和她那闪闪发亮的轨迹
Her silhouette
虽说那个背影
looks so distant,
一直都是那么地遥远
but if I work hard enough, I will be able to catch up to her,
但只要不停努力 总有一天一定会追上她
to the dream I have.
绝对追上那理想的姿态
My aspiration
那心中憧憬的背影
is my motivation.
就是这个想法让我奔跑至今
Welcome to Tracen Academy's Orientation Day.
欢迎来到特雷森学园的校园说明会
What is your name?
你们叫什么名字
I'm Kitasan Black.
我是北部玄驹
I'm Satono Diamond.
我是里见光钻
I will not forget your name.
好 我会记得的
The disadvantageous position will not stop her.
就算从是不利的外侧 也阻止不了她
Tokai Teio
东海帝皇
is the champion of the Japanese Derby!
夺下日本德比
Tokai Teio!
东海帝皇 是东海帝皇
Tokai Teio made a comeback!
东海帝皇 以奇迹之姿复活了
She is amazing.
她真的好厉害
She shines so brightly.
真的好耀眼
ENTRANCE CEREMONY
(入学典礼)
Today is the day, Diamond.
终于来到这一天了呢 光钻
Let's work hard together, Kita.
是啊 一起加油吧 小北
Now that I'm in the academy
进入特雷森学园
and have debuted, I'm one step closer to her.
然后出道 稍微接近了她一点
With that in mind,
抱着这样的想法
I look ahead
看着眼前
and run.
拼命奔跑
I run and run.
不断地奔跑
But
然而…
deep down, I can feel it.
我其实隐隐约约察觉到了
I
我…
will never…
肯定是…
Be like them.
无法成为的吧…
I'm going for a small jog now.
那我出发去慢跑了哦
Be safe.
路上小心
Kita doesn't look that well.
北部没什么精神呢
I hope she is eating properly.
不知道她有没有好好吃饭呢
She has enough rest by now,
身体的疲劳应该都恢复了
but her motivation is gone.
看来是提不起干劲呢
Forcing her to run at this point is a recipe for disaster.
要是在这种状况下勉强她的话 可能会出现重大意外的
We can't rush her.
不能着急对吧
Shouldn't you be worried?
你不担心吗
Our junior is in a slump.
可爱的学妹在烦恼着呢
She'll be fine.
没事的
Kita will be fine.
小北肯定没问题的
Have you heard?
你们几个听说了吗
It's huge.
有大新闻啊
Everyone in Spica must be worried about me.
Spica的各位都在担心我吧
I have to get myself together.
不能老是这么丧志
Dwelling on it won't change anything.
这样下去不会有任何改变的
But
但是…
no matter how hard I try…
就算我再怎么努力…
A distal radius fracture that'll need six months to recover.
是桡骨远端骨折 要六个月才能痊愈
She is unable to take part in any races this year.
今年恐怕是无法再参加任何比赛了
I repeat,
为各位重复一次
Duramente, who won Satsuki Sho
今年勇夺皋月赏与日本德比冠军的
"DURAMENTE, INJURED" and Japanese Derby, is suffering
(大鸣大放骨折无法参加菊花赏 ) 二冠赛马娘 大鸣大放
"UNABLE TO RACE IN KIKUKA SHO" from a bone fracture.
惊传骨折的消息
A bone fracture?
骨折…
She was expected to win the last crown
她身为秋天举行的
this autumn in Kikuka Sho.
菊花赏的冠军候补
This news has made the outcome of Kikuka Sho all the more unpredictable.
这么一来 这场比赛将会如何发展
At the moment, Duramente boasts a record of four wins out of six races.
大鸣大放的战绩为6战4胜
She was the runner-up in two of the races.
两次分别为第二名 战绩惊人
This year, she won Satsuki Sho
还拿下了今天经典三冠的皋月赏
and the Japanese Derby, two of the triple crowns.
以及日本德比的冠军
One might say that she is the best horse girl at the moment.
可说是经典世代最强的二冠赛马娘
Many fans expect Duramente to win
当然她身为秋季开赛的 菊花赏冠军候补
Kikuka Sho too, which will take place in autumn.
身受全国赛马娘粉丝的期待
Her injury will undoubtedly upset her loyal fans
这次受伤骨折 想必会让很多粉丝失望
as they look forward to watching her win all three crowns.
原本期待她是下一位三冠赛马娘 真的很遗憾
Moving on, in the Grand Prix that is happening tomorrow,
下一则新闻 是将在明天举办的大奖赛
Takarazuka Kinen
宝冢纪念
-was voted for two years consecutively… -I… I…
-两次蝉联粉丝投票第一名… -太逊了…
"UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3" I suck.
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》 我太差劲了
She's fast and strong but she can't take part in Kikuka Sho now?
那种又快又强的人 没办法参加菊花赏吗
Yes.
是啊
I didn't expect her injury to be this serious…
虽说是受伤 但也太…
This reminds me of you, Nice Nature.
感觉跟那个时候的优秀素质很像呢
Can you believe it? Duramente is injured.
真是的 不会吧 大鸣大放
She's not going to compete in autumn.
看来她在秋天是无法出赛了
You know she'd win
要是出赛 她就会是三冠
Kikuka Sho easily. She'd have all three crowns.
菊花赏肯定是手到擒来
But other horse girls now stand a chance.
但是这样的话 其他的赛马娘不就有机会了吗
Come on.
我说你啊…
This reminds me of what happened to Teio.
让我想起了那个时候的帝皇呢
Exactly.
我懂 我也是
I feel sorry for Duramente.
大鸣大放真的很可怜呢
Me too.
就是啊
I wonder if Kita is doing all right.
不知道小北她要不要紧
She should be back soon.
我想她应该快回来了
When she knows that Duramente is injured…
但她要是知道大鸣大放受伤的话…
She will be devastated.
一定会很不甘心吧
She was hoping for a rematch.
她很想在这次报一箭之仇的
Yeah.
是啊
To be denied a rematch,
想要一起比赛却没有机会
I know how bad this feels.
我很能体会这种心情
Let's cheer her up once she's back.
等她回来后 我们给她加油打气吧
We'll help her regain her focus for the next race.
让她心无旁骛地去比赛
Okay.
是啊
Should I make a nutritious drink for Kita?
对了 要不要做个营养饮料 来给小北喝呢
You should!
赞成…
I… I…
我…
Are you all right?
怎么啦
Nice Nature…
优秀素质…
-I know. -Turbo.
-我知道 -涡轮
Here.
给你
Thank you.
谢谢你
You're welcome.
不用客气
Tannhauser bought it but no one
虽然是唐怀瑟买的就是了
wanted to drink it. I was trying to get rid of it.
但完全没人要喝 正伤脑筋呢
Are you skipping your training?
你是不想参加训练吗
You lazy bum.
真是个懒惰鬼呢
Is it about Kikuka Sho?
是因为菊花赏的事吗
Maybe I can help you if you tell me what's bothering you.
有什么心事的话 不妨可以试着说出来
Certain things are easier to talk about
你看 像是这种事 比起说给身边亲近的人听
when you're with strangers instead of friends.
面对无关紧要的人 也比较说得出口吧
I can be your listener.
不嫌弃的话 我可以倾听哦
It's bitter.
好苦…
I aspire
我一直很憧憬
to be someone like Teio,
我一直想要成为帝皇那样的人
to be a star like her.
想要成为像她那样的明星
But I don't have it in me.
但是我没办法
It's the truth.
我看清楚了
Only people like Duramente can achieve what Teio did.
大鸣大放那样的人 才有办法成为帝皇那般的存在
She won Satsuki Sho and Derby.
夺下了皋月赏和德比
She drew fans with her gait and her awesome performance.
用那吸引众人目光的凌厉跑法 还有那帅气的身影
I have none of them.
那都是我没有的
After the news of her injury broke out,
刚刚看到了她骨折的新闻
everyone felt sorry for her because
所有人都因为 她无法夺得三冠而遗憾
she couldn't get her triple crown anymore.
为她担心
And I noticed
我才注意到
that was what everyone did to Teio too.
她就连这一点 也和帝皇一模一样
It sucks that she can't attend the next race because of her injury.
我明明知道她因为受伤 不能出赛已经很难受了
But everyone giving her attention
觉得所有人都在注视着大鸣大放
just makes me feel worse about myself.
光这么想就已经很差劲了
I…
我甚至还想…
I even had the thought
如果她没有出赛的话
that if she is absent,
我说不定能赢下菊花赏…
maybe I can win Kikuka Sho…
脑里闪过了这个想法…
People like me will never succeed,
像我这种人 根本就成为不了
will never be a superstar like Teio.
成为像帝皇那样帅气 闪闪发亮的明星…
I get what you mean.
哎呀 我懂这种感觉
I
我啊
used to idolize Teio too.
曾经也很憧憬帝皇
She
帝皇她啊…
was a natural-born superstar.
就是那种天生的明星吧
She's wonderful. She's honest.
又闪亮又率直
She's hardworking.
但她也非常努力
And she has the talent.
强得不得了
After her injury in the Derby,
那样的她在德比后骨折
she did everything she could to speed up her recovery.
但她绝不轻言放弃 一直持续复健
Her perseverance inspired me.
她的那个样子也激励了我
It made me want to join and win Kikuka Sho.
让我想要参加菊花赏 并赢下它
So I did. I won four races in a row
然后我就一鼓作气拿到了四连胜
and got my ticket to Kikuka Sho.
成功夺下参加菊花赏的门票
And then I thought
然后我就想到了
that if Teio couldn't make it to the race,
要是帝皇来不及出赛 那说不定…
maybe I would stand a chance too…
就连这样的我也会有机会…
Ultimately, I wanted to win.
因为我想赢啊
Isn't that normal?
这不是理所当然吗
I don't want to be in third place or second place.
不是第三名 也不是第二名
I want to be the champion.
我想要得到冠军
However,
但是…
when I had that kind of thought, I felt ashamed,
对于马上产生这样想法的自己 觉得很丢脸
mad.
觉得很生气
Like what you're feeling now, Kita.
简单的说 就是跟现在的北部一样
Nature…
优秀素质…
It's a bittersweet feeling, isn't it?
很不甘心对吧
People talk about either
一下是帝皇 一下是大鸣大放
Teio or Duramente.
人们都在谈论这些出色的人
They think other candidates in Kikuka Sho are bad
说这次的菊花赏没有能人
and that if Duramente was there, she would surely win it.
还说要是她能出赛 肯定能得到三冠
I was angry when I heard those things.
我越听越生气
So I decided to win.
所以我决定要赢
I wanted them to notice me.
要他们看着我
I wouldn't let them think that I won because Teio was absent.
绝对不让他们说 我是因为帝皇不在才赢的
I ran with that in my mind,
抱着这样的想法在奔跑
till they noticed me.
让他们看看我在这里
Even though I might be weak, lame, and opportunistic,
就算既狡猾又弱小还很逊
I found myself that day.
但我跑出了自我
I think that was the beginning of my journey.
我想那就是我的起点吧
Even though I only got fourth place in the end.
虽然结果只得了第四名就是了
Beginning of the journey…
起点…
Giving my all…
跑出自我…
Finding myself…
我不明白
How do I find myself on the track?
到底要如何…才能跑出自我
That's a difficult question.
这是个难题呢
I'm still trying to find an answer.
我现在也还在思考这个问题
I don't have confidence either.
我也没有自信
After Derby, I feel inadequate.
在德比结束后 就开始感到害怕
I get it.
我懂…
I always feel inadequate as well.
我也一直都没有自信呢
But…
但是…
Still…
即使如此…
I…
果然…
I want to win.
我还是想赢
I want to win more races.
我想赢下更多比赛
Prove the naysayers wrong then.
那就让那些说这次没有能人的 家伙们见识一下吧
Can I do it?
我做得到吗
Definitely.
可以的…
You're better than me.
你比我这种人厉害太多了
Even though I'm weak, lame, and maybe opportunistic?
就算既狡猾又弱小还很逊也是吗
All of them
就是包括了这些
are part of you, aren't they?
你才会是北部玄驹不是吗
I see.
这样啊
Thank you.
谢谢你
Nature, you are a great company.
优秀素质 你是个好人呢
What are you on about?
你这孩子是在胡说什么呢
Drink some tea.
好了 快喝茶吧
Okay.
是
It is bitter.
好苦
I knew it.
果然吗…
She hasn't returned.
她还不回来吗
She must still be upset about Duramente.
一定是知道了大鸣大放的事 在失落吧
Yeah.
是啊…
It's okay.
没问题的
She'll be fine after this nutritious drink.
只要喝下这个营养饮料 她一定能打起精神的
I'm back.
我回来了
-Kitasan. -Kita.
-北部… -小北…
U—Uhm…
那…那个
I will continue to work hard
我接下来会继续努力
and I hope all of you can continue guiding me.
所以还请大家继续鞭策我
Let's win Kikuka Sho.
好 那我们就来拿下菊花赏吧
Yes!
是
I'll get some training done now.
那我马上去练跑
You can do it tomorrow!
明天再开始练啦
I can never be someone like Teio.
我无法成为像帝皇那样的人
And that's okay.
但是 就算这样也没关系
I'm weak, lame, and maybe opportunistic.
就算既弱小又狡猾还很逊
But that's me.
但这就是我
I won't be a superstar.
就算无法成为明星
I won't be the highlight.
就算无法闪闪发光
I won't be the centre of the attention.
就算不是主角
But still, I will climb.
也要不断挣扎
I will get up.
不断爬起
The final race of Autumn G1 is here.
好的 秋季的GI 也来到了最后的一场比赛
We are here at Kikuka Sho, the last crown in the triple crown.
来到了经典三冠赛 最后的菊花赏
Albeit winning Satsuki Sho and the Japanese Derby,
虽然拿下了皋月赏 以及日本德比的大鸣大放
Duramente cannot be here due to her injury.
因为伤势无法参赛
I'm sure the fans here would love to witness her triple crown moment.
相信很多粉丝 也很期待她能夺得三冠吧
What a shame.
真的很遗憾
It's okay if no one notices me.
没人在意也没关系
I don't care if no one sings my praises.
我也不在乎有没有人会夸奖我
I will find myself
我要不顾一切
on this track.
跑出自我
I will run for myself.
为自己而跑
All candidates are now at the starting gate.
好的 所有赛马娘已在闸门就位
In this breezy Kyoto,
在这秋风凉爽的京都
who will win this year's
会夺得经典三冠赛菊花赏的人
Kikuka Sho?
究竟会是谁呢
Go!
起跑了
Kid Dansatsu is off to a late start.
幼童珍宝大幅落后
She's way behind everyone else.
远远地被抛在了后头
Go!
冲啊…
-We're heading to the bend. -Go!
-就要进入弯道了 -冲啊…
Parol and Ribbon Pastoral
帕洛尔及缎带牧歌这两位
are competing for the first spot.
依然激烈地在争夺首位
Will this be a war of attrition?
这会变成消耗战吗
The leading Parol and Ribbon Pastoral
领先的是帕洛尔及缎带牧歌
are still moving forward.
不停地向前冲去
They say only the best horse girl can win
相传在经典三冠赛中的 最后一场赛事 菊花赏
Kikuka Sho, the last leg of the Classic Triple Crown.
只有最强的赛马娘能够胜出
Do you know why?
你知道这是为什么吗
Why?
为什么突然说这个
Because you need both speed and stamina in this race.
因为这是场必须兼具速度和体力
You have to overcome two slopes and run a 3,000-meter track
还得克服两个坡道 以及长达三千米的跑道
to win.
才有办法夺得胜利
Also, Kikuka Sho was inspired by England's St Leger Stakes.
顺道一提 这个赛事也是以 英国的"圣烈治"为范本
So it's also called the Japanese St Legers.
也就是京都农林省赏典…
Go, Kitasan Black!
冲啊 北部玄驹…
How is she doing?
她的状况如何啊
It seems like she is quite behind.
看起来好像被拉开了距离
It's not bad.
还不坏
But not great either.
虽说如此 但也说不上是好
So what is it then?
到底是好还是不好…
Do not underestimate the length of the course.
不能小看这三千米
Among the Classic Three Crown,
对经典级的赛马娘来说
this is her first long-distance race.
这种长距离赛事是首次
So everyone is on equal footing.
大家的机会是相同的
With their eyes set on the trophy,
好的 心怀对菊花的梦想
all athletes are doing their best to perform.
以此为动力奔驰着
They are now approaching the second bend.
各赛马娘进入了第二弯道
In the second slope,
虽然进入了第二个坡道
the ranking keeps changing.
但排名不断产生变化
I will climb.
不断挣扎
I will get back up.
不断爬起
I won't give up.
紧咬不放
I will run.
不断奔跑…
They have now arrived at the part between the third and the fourth bend.
好的 各赛马娘来到了 第三第四弯道的中间地点
They will descend now.
开始下坡了
Gentsu Steel occupies the centre.
玄津钢铁占住了中间的位置
I will not shine brightly like a superstar,
就算无法像明星般 闪闪发亮也没关系
but that is okay.
我就是我
For I am Kitasan Black.
我就是北部玄驹
600 meters left. We are heading to the fourth bend.
剩下600米 进入第四弯道了
Go!
冲啊
And now, the final stretch.
来到了最后直线
All horse girls are sprinting with all their might.
所有赛马娘进入最后冲剌
Kitasan Black charged out from the inside line.
北部玄驹从最内侧冲上来了
I…
所以…
Will start from here.
我要从这里
Kitasan Black is accelerating.
北部玄驹冲出来了
Kitasan Black.
北部玄驹…
She overtook Jewel Sapphire from the side.
一口气从外侧超越了珠宝蓝宝石
Gentsu Steel is in the middle.
玄津钢铁在中间
Gentsu Steel speeds up too.
玄津钢铁也从中间冲上来了
She speeds up from the centre.
玄津钢铁从中间一口气冲出来了
Kita!
小北
Go!
冲啊…
Kitasan Black takes the lead.
北部玄驹领先
A festival. This is a festival.
祭典 这是祭典啊
A Kitasan festival!
是北部的祭典啊
Kitasan Black won!
获胜的是北部玄驹
Kita!
小北
Sheesh.
真是的
You are shining like a star too.
你不也是闪闪发光吗
See? I told you. Kita will be fine.
所以我不是说了吗 小北没问题的
We got all worried for nothing.
看来是我们瞎操心了呢
For all you know,
说不定啊
Kita might surpass me as a horse girl.
小北会成为比我还厉害的赛马娘呢
Shouldn't you tell her that yourself?
这句话你不去跟她说吗
I will not because I don't want to lose to her either.
会很不甘心所以不说
Thank you!
谢谢大家
This is the beginning of my journey.
这里就是我的起点
It's not the most awesome start.
就算不能很帅气
But it allows me to persevere,
但这也是为了让我继续前进的…
to…
是我的…
EPISODE 2: STARTING LINE
(第2话 起跑线)